<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Prehensile Tail</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Prehensile Tail</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A few Akka posts</title>
      <link>/posts/2012/08/a-few-akka-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012/08/a-few-akka-posts/</guid>
      <description>Update: unfortunately, the Safari Books blog no longer seems to be around, so the following links are all broken. And consequently, the articles are now lost.
Recently I was asked to write a few posts for the Safari Books Online blog. They were looking for Scala content, so I suggested Akka as a central theme. I wrote these posts with an audience in mind that hopefully would have been exposed to Scala (or could, at least, read a short Scala tutorial), but who had not yet written any Akka code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A reading list for JVM-based developers</title>
      <link>/posts/2011/11/a-jvm-based-developers-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011/11/a-jvm-based-developers-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>The other day, I found myself in a series of discussions with some fellow developers, in part about the performance characteristics of large numbers of threads in a JVM running on a Linux system. While I would not claim to be any sort of expert on the subject, it was clear that some of the information I had thought was fairly well known, was not nearly as pervasive as I assumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Haskell Hacking with Emacs</title>
      <link>/posts/2011/11/quick-haskell-hacking-with-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2011/11/quick-haskell-hacking-with-emacs/</guid>
      <description>A couple days ago I was playing around with my Emacs configuration a bit and decided to see if I could find ways to make it a more direct part of my flow (whatever the hell that means). For a quick sample of sorts, I threw together this little hack that let&amp;rsquo;s me popup a quick Emacs window with a buffer that&amp;rsquo;s already running haskell-mode (I assume here that you already have it installed, if not, you can find info on the haskell-mode page).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>